Guide to the James Lippincott Goodwin Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- James L. Goodwin Ledgers, 1928-1965; Series XII
  - L2 Great Pond Nursery and Forestry Accounts, 1942-1957 (Box 107)
  - L3 Great Pond Nursery and Forestry Accounts, 1948-1958 (Box 107)
  - L4 Great Pond Nursery and Forestry Accounts, 1950-1955 (Box 107)
  - L5 Great Pond Nursery and Forestry Accounts, 1958-1965 (Box 108)
  - L6 Great Pond Nursery and Forestry Accounts, 1963-1965 (Box 108)
  - L7 Pine Acres Farm, Chaplin Forest Timber Records, 1928 (Box 108)
  - L8 Pine Acres Farm, Chaplin, Orchard Hill Forest Timber Records, 1928 (Box 108)
  - L9 Pine Acres Farm, Hampton Forest Timber Records, 1928 (Box 108)
  - L10 Pine Acres Farm, Hampton Forest, Orchard Hill Forest Accounts, 1929-1941 (Box 109)
  - L11 Pine Acres Farm, Farm and Forestry Accounts, 1930-1949 (Box 109)
  - L12 Pine Acres Farm, Farm and Forestry Accounts, 1933-1937 (Box 109)
  - L13 Pine Acres Farm, Farm and Forestry Accounts, 1938-1941 (Box 110)
  - L14 Pine Acres Farm, Pine Plantation Journal, 1940-1949 (Box 110A)
  - L15 Pine Acres Farm, Farm and Forestry Accounts, 1941-1961 (Box 111)
  - L16 Pine Acres Farm, Farm and Forestry Accounts, 1942-1944 (Box 112)
  - L17 Pine Acres Farm, Farm and Forestry Accounts, 1945-1958 (Box 113)
  - L18 Pine Acres Farm, Farm and Forestry Accounts, 1949 (Box 114)
  - L19 Pine Acres Farm, Farm and Forestry Accounts, 1952-1955 (Box 115)
  - L20 Pine Acres Farm, Farm and Forestry Accounts, 1956-1958 (Box 116)
  - L21 Pine Acres Farm, Farm and Forestry Accounts, 1959-1961 (Box 117)
  - L22 Pine Acres Farm, Depreciation Records Accounts, 1961-1971 (Box 118)
  - L23 Pine Acres Farm, Farm and Forestry Accounts, 1962 (Box 119)
  - L24 Pine Acres Farm, Farm and Forestry Accounts, 1963 (Box 119)
  - L25 Pine Acres Farm, Forest and Wild Life Records, 1963 (Box 120)
  - L26 Pine Acres Farm, Man Labor Records, 1964 (Box 120)
- Maps Included in James L. Goodwin Papers, 1916-1964; Series XIII
  - Maps of Pine Acres Farm, Circa 1916-1964 (Box 121)
    Includes Pine Plantation, Clark's Corner; Orchard Hill, Hampton and Chaplin Tracts; Pine Acres Plantation and Progress; Orchard Hill Forest; Cedar Swamps; Cruise Line, Chaplin Forest; Hampton Town; Cartwright Tract; Jewett and Clark Piece; Ford Piece, Hampton; and Goodwin property in Hartford.
    - Additional material (Box 121A)
    - Additional material (Box 121B)
  - Maps of Shaker Pines Forest, Hazardville, Connecticut, 1936-1937
    - Shaker Pines Forest, 1938 (Box 122)
    - Timber Strand, Hazardville, 1937 (Box 122)
  - Maps of Great Pond Nursery, Simsbury, Connecticut, 1928-1953, 1965, 1966
    - Eddy and Goodwin Tracts, Simsbury, 1928, 1929, 1930 (Box 122)
    - Great Pond, 1950, 1953 (Box 122)
    - Great Pond Forest, 1965 (Box 122)
    - Sketch of Whitman Property, 1966 (Box 122)
    - Great Pond Nursery, 1953, Simsbury (Box 122)
  - Maps of Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association, 1929-1937
    - Talcott Mountain - Avon and West Hartford, 1929, 1933, 1937 (Box 123)
    - Trail Maps and Reservoirs, 1933 (Box 123)
    - Goodwin-Talcott Holdings, 1925 (Box 123)
    - Talcott Mountain Property, n. d. (Box 123)
    - Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association, 1933 (Box 123)
    - Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association, 1929 (Box 123)
  - Maps of Carthage Plantation, Carthage, North Carolina, 1930-1952
    - Moore County Maps, 1930-1936 (Box 124)
    - Forest type Maps of Carthage including tracts and compartments: (Box 124)
    - 1928, 1929, 1930, 1932, 1934, 1946, Cuttings of Pine and Hardwoods, 1942-1949 (Box 124)
    - Rillett's Creek, Carthage, 1928, 1927 (Box 124)
    - Property of James L. Goodwin, Moore County, Carthage, 1942 (Box 124)
    - North Carolina County Road Survey, Carthage, 1930 (Box 124)
  - Maps of Goodwin's Connecticut Area Holdings and Interests, Circa 1890-1956 (Box 125)
    Includes Loomis Institute, Hartland; Granby Mountain Farms, De Graft, West Grandy; Griffith, East Granby; Hickory Hill, Woodruff, Simsbury; Holcomb, Salter, Tuler, Ensign, Goddard, Woodworth, Gidlung, McKeenen (all Simsbury); Rowley, Furlong, and Garrity (all West Simsbury); Camp Rainbow, Hartford, and Windsor; Cascio, North Granby; Ellsworth Weatogue; Peoples Forest, Barkhampstead; and Scott, Avon.
    - Additional material (Box 125A)
    - Additional material (Box 125B)
  - Blue prints and specifications, James L. Goodwin house, Woodside Circle, (Philip L. Goodwin, Architect); plans for house, Philip L. Goodwin, Woodbury, Long Island. (Box 126)
- Additional material, 1907-1911, 1938; Accession 1994-M-022; 0.25; (1 box)
  Addition inventory by Diane E. Kaplan 1993 Sep
  Received from: Forest History Society, Inc., 1993 Sep 14
  - Album containing photographs from Yale Forestry School camps in Pennsylvania and Louisiana. The album also includes photographs of Vermont and of hurricane damage in Hartford, 1907-1911, 1938 (Box 1)